Divine Elikplim Abah

Creative Designer, Marketer & UI/UX Developer

East Legon, Greater Accra, Ghana, 0233 +233 20 195 5961 | +233 20 195 5962 | +233 50 305 1058 DIVINE.E.ABAH@GMAIL.COM www.deeveli.vercel.app

About me

I am a wear-many-hats kind of creative designer and front-end developer, with 3 years of marketing experience to boot. For the past 3 years, I've been creating UI and UX designs for web and mobile apps and marketing products online, leveraging 7 years plus of visual design experience to create beautiful interfaces and drawing out the right audience. I'm fluent in the latest tech, ie., HTML5, Typescript, React (Next.js), Wordpress (Elementor), Framer and getting up to speed with Flutter. I love art and customer experience, feels like ecstasy. My ultimate goal? Think of marketing magic mixed with coding expertise, resulting in stunning and functional interfaces that drive real results!

Skills

- Front-End Development:
 - Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (TypeScript), Dart, Wordpress (PHP)
 - o Libraries: jQuery, GraphQL
 - o Frameworks: React (Next.js), Flutter
- UI/UX Design: Figma Dev, Adobe XD
- Marketing: Social Media Ad Campaigns, Media Buying, Market Research, Reporting
- Version Control: GitUnit Testing: Jest

Experience

Mobile/Web Application Frontend Engineer | UI/UX Designer

Steaman Group, East Legon, Ghana

November 2024 - Present

- Ensure websites and apps look good and work well at Steaman Group.
- Build fast, easy-to-use web and mobile apps as a Frontend Application Engineer.
- Design how apps and websites should look and feel as the Lead UI/UX Designer.
- Create simple and attractive designs, test them, and ensure easy usability.
- Work closely with developers, designers, and marketers to deliver the best user experience.
- Combine design and coding to create digital products that help businesses and users.

Creative and Web Developer

Swiss Group Limited, Spintex, Ghana

May 2024 - October 2024

- **Designed and developed** website using Adobe XD, Next.js, Framer, and relevant libraries, prioritizing user experience and lead conversions.
- Set up marketing ad campaigns which has driven sales up, and also reaching the right target audience.
- Collaborated with marketing team to ensure seamless campaign strategies.
- Increased user engagement on all online activities by 20% from the first month to date through brand redesig and customer nurturing implementations..

Creative and Applications Developer

Axxend Corporation, East Legon, Ghana

August 2023 - January 2024

- Implemented UI/UX strategies to improve user interactions on various platforms.
- Produced and managed media contents, including graphics and videos, for diverse projects.
- Conducted market research and analysis to identify trends and inform marketing decisions.

Creatives Associate

Pearson Consultancy (Axxend Corporation Subsidiary), East Legon, Ghana

October 2021 – July 2023

- Designed WordPress websites and Power App solutions, focusing on user experience and visual appeal.
- Implemented UI/UX strategies to enhance user interactions across various platforms.
- Managed media content creation, including graphics and videos, to support diverse project requirements.
- Conducted market research and analysis to identify user trends and inform design decisions.

Graphic Designer and WordPress Developer

Artrixs Multimedia, East Legon, Ghana

October 2018 - August 2020

- Designed, developed, and maintained WordPress websites.
- Created compelling graphics and written content for blogs, contributing to increased user engagement.
- Managed SEO strategies and optimized content for improved search engine rankings.

Website Redesign, Steaman Heights

Steaman Heights, East Legon, Ghana, 1 Month, May 2024

• Designed a responsive real estate website, crafting a user-friendly experience to showcase Steaman Heights properties and capture leads for potential buyers.

E-Commerce Website Redesign, Steaman Mall GH

Steaman Mall, East Legon, Ghana, 1 Month, May 2024

 Designed Steaman Group's e-commerce website, focusing on enhancing the user experience and interface design. Created interactive UI components to aid development, optimizing overall customer interactions and increase buying intentions.

Website Redesign, Swiss Group Limited

Swiss Group Limited, Spintex, Ghana, 1 Month, May 2024

• I am currently spearheading the UI/UX design and development for the SGL Auto Dealership Website. Prioritized enhancements in user experience, interface design, and lead capture. Implemented responsive design strategies and streamlined site performance for optimal functionality.

Education

BSc. Computer Engineering

Ghana Communications Technology University, Tesano, Ghana

September 2017 – November 2021

Digital Global Marketer

Aleph Digital, Africa

April 2023 - July 2023

User Experience Design

Accenture UK, offered by Vodafone Ghana (FutureLearn),

October 2020 - November 2020

Certificates

- Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering
- User Experience, Accenture
- Digital Global Marketer

Reference

Head of Technology and Infrastructure, Axxend Corporation

+233 50 139 4289

Mrs. Boateng Priscilla

Marketing Lead, Pearson Group

+233 27 423 4667

Mr. Kwarteng Justice

Head of Training, Axxend Corporation

+233 20 251 0856